A Guide to the Records of the Clan MacLeod Society USA, 1899-2009
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Dunvegan Foundation 1954-2009.
  - Annual Giving
    - Where does all the money go? (Box-folder 54:23)
    - Bound journal of donations December 1, 1981 to October 31, 1988 (Box-folder 54:24)
  - Board of Trustees
    - Area representatives: associates program (Box-folder 54:25)
    - Board of trust lists (Box-folder 54:26)
    - Dunvegan foundation information (Box-folder 55:1)
    - Trustees: flow charts/ list 1993 (Box-folder 55:2)
    - Explanation of society and foundation relationships, a brief history drafted by Dr. Alexander MacLeod 1993 (Box-folder 55:3)
    - Foundation promotion/publicity memo (undated) (Box-folder 55:4)
    - Job descriptions for officers/roles and responsibilities for associates and trustees (Box-folder 55:5)
    - Leadership expectations and mission (Box-folder 55:6)
    - Meetings of the Dunvegan Foundation 1954-1957 (Box-folder 55:7)
    - Meetings 1961 (Box-folder 55:8)
    - Meetings 1968 (Box-folder 55:9)
    - Meetings 1977 (Box-folder 55:10)
    - Meetings 1978 (Box-folder 55:11)
    - Meetings 1980 (Box-folder 55:12)
    - Meetings 1981 (Box-folder 55:13)
    - Meetings 1982 (Box-folder 55:14)
    - Meetings 1983 (Box-folder 55:15)
    - Meetings 1984 (Box-folder 55:16)
    - Meetings 1985 (Box-folder 55:17)
    - Meetings 1986 (Box-folder 55:18)
    - Meetings 1987 (Box-folder 55:19)
    - Meetings 1988 (Box-folder 55:20)
    - Meetings 1989 (Box-folder 55:21)
    - Meetings 1990 (Box-folder 55:22)
    - Meetings 1991 (Box-folder 55:23)
    - Meetings 1992 (Box-folder 55:24)
    - Meetings 1993 (Box-folder 55:25)
    - Meetings 1994 (Box-folder 55:26)
    - Meetings 1995 (Box-folder 55:27)
    - Meetings 1996 (Box-folder 55:28)
    - Meetings 1997 (Box-folder 55:29)
    - Meetings 2003 (Box-folder 55:30)
    - Nominations for Officers of the Society and Trustees of the Dunvegan Castle Foundation 1960-61 (Box-folder 56:1)
    - Nominations for Clan Council and the Dunvegan Board of Trustees April 1982 (Box-folder 56:2)
    - An open letter concerning dignity to the Council of the Society and Trustees of The Dunvegan Foundation of the Clan MacLeod Society, USA 1994 (Box-folder 56:3)
    - Resolutions 1988 (Box-folder 56:4)
    - Sayre MacLeod information 1987 (Box-folder 56:5)
    - Trustees/Associates roles and responsibilities (Box-folder 56:6)
    - Rotation of trustees (Box-folder 56:7)
    - Trustee questionnaire (Box-folder 56:8)
    - William Reynold McLeod?s resignation from the Board of Trustees January 7. 1991 (Box-folder 56:9)
    - Trustee structure and goals (Box-folder 56:10)
    - Trustees' survey? (Box-folder 56:11)
    - Trustee time report 1993 (Box-folder 56:12)
    - What Are We Doing? A position paper concerning the Dunvegan Foundation November 11, 1992 (Box-folder 56:13)
  - Committees
    - Advisory committee (Box-folder 56:14)
    - Committee on benevolences in Scotland (Box-folder 56:15)
    - Development committee (Box-folder 56:16)
    - Nominating committee (Box-folder 56:17)
    - Planning/Review committee: mission and goals (Box-folder 56:18)
    - Standing committee (Box-folder 56:19)
  - Corporate Documents
    - Dunvegan Foundation calendars (Box-folder 56:20)
    - Dunvegan Foundation declaration of trust and by-laws (Box-folder 56:21)
    - Dunvegan Foundation sourcebook (Box-folder 56:22)
    - Notes on Dunvegan Foundation incorporation (Box-folder 56:23)
    - Notice of employer identification number (Box-folder 56:24)
    - Resolution of board of directors (authority to open deposit account) 1985 (Box-folder 56:25)
    - Dunvegan Foundation: mission statement (Box-folder 56:26)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence 1957,1959 (Box-folder 57:1)
    - Correspondence 1960-1961, 1963 (Box-folder 57:2)
    - Correspondence 1965-1967, 1967, 1969 (Box-folder 57:3)
    - Correspondence 1975,1977 (Box-folder 57:4)
    - Correspondence 1979-1981 (Box-folder 57:5)
    - Correspondence 1982 (Box-folder 57:6)
    - Correspondence 1983 (Box-folder 57:7)
    - Correspondence 1984 (Box-folder 57:8)
    - Correspondence 1985 (Box-folder 57:9)
    - Correspondence 1986 (Box-folder 57:10)
    - Correspondence 1987 (Box-folder 57:11)
    - Correspondence 1988 (Box-folder 57:12)
    - Correspondence 1989 (Box-folder 58:1)
    - Correspondence 1990 (Box-folder 58:2)
    - Correspondence 1991 (I) (Box-folder 58:3)
    - Correspondence 1991 (II) (Box-folder 58:4)
    - Correspondence 1992 (I) (Box-folder 58:5)
    - Correspondence 1992 (II) (Box-folder 58:6)
    - Correspondence 1992 (III) (Box-folder 58:7)
    - Correspondence 1992 (IV) (Box-folder 58:8)
    - Correspondence 1993 (I) (Box-folder 59:1)
    - Correspondence 1993 (II) (Box-folder 59:2)
    - Correspondence 1993 (III) (Box-folder 59:3)
    - Correspondence 1993 (IV) (Box-folder 59:4)
    - Correspondence 1994 (I) (Box-folder 59:5)
    - Correspondence 1994 (II) (Box-folder 59:6)
    - Correspondence 1994 (III) (Box-folder 60:1)
    - Correspondence 1995 (Box-folder 60:2)
    - Correspondence 1996 (Box-folder 60:3)
    - Correspondence 1997 (Box-folder 60:4)
    - Correspondence 1998 (Box-folder 60:5)
    - Correspondence 1999 (Box-folder 60:6)
    - Correspondence 2000- (Box-folder 60:7)
    - Correspondence (undated) (Box-folder 60:8)
  - Dunvegan Castle Foundation
    - Declaration of Trust (Box-folder 61:1)
    - Dunvegan Foundation mission (Box-folder 61:2)
    - Dunvegan Castle Foundation booklet (Box-folder 61:3)
    - Article: MacLeod clan gathers to save old castle 1950s (Box-folder 61:4)
  - Expenses
    - Expense statements 1991, 1993, 1994 (Box-folder 61:5)
    - Housekeeping summary 1992 (?) (Box-folder 61:6)
    - Invoices and receipts pertaining to the Dunvegan Foundation 1979-1994 (Box-folder 61:7)
    - Mailing service costs (Box-folder 61:8)
    - Statement of receipts and disbursements January 1 to September 30, 1986 (Box-folder 61:9)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: General
    - Commercial blanket bond-insurance 1985-86 (Box-folder 61:10)
    - Commercial insurance policies (Box-folder 61:11)
    - Documents pertaining to stocks and bonds (Box-folder 61:12)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: Banking
    - Copy of Advertisement documents from American Banker (Box-folder 61:13)
    - Bruceton Bank: deposited checks 1986-1990 (Box-folder 61:14)
    - Chemical Bank: deposited checks 1974-1984 (Box-folder 61:15)
    - Check stubs from Chemical Bank New York Trust Company November 1, 1960 to July 15, 1980 (Box-folder 61:16)
    - Chemical Bank: correspondence (Box-folder 61:17)
    - Chemical Bank: deposit receipts 1972-1984 (Box-folder 61:18)
    - Chemical Bank: CD receipt endowment fund July 29, 1983 (Box-folder 61:19)
    - Transactions with Chemical Bank and Marine Midland Bank (Box-folder 61:20)
    - Transactions with Chemical Bank and Royal Bank of Scotland (Box-folder 61:21)
    - Closing of the Chemical Bank account 1984 (Box-folder 61:22)
    - Escrow account (Box-folder 61:23)
    - First American Bank: correspondence (Box-folder 61:24)
    - First National Bank: check stubs 1982-1984 (Box-folder 61:25)
    - First American Bank: deposited checks 1982-1992 (Box-folder 62:1)
    - First American Bank: documents (Box-folder 62:2)
    - First American Bank: bookkeeping records (Box-folder 62:3)
    - First American Bank: financial records (Box-folder 62:4)
    - First American Bank and IRS (Box-folder 62:5)
    - J.C Bradford Account (Box-folder 62:6)
    - Marine Midland Bank: correspondence (Box-folder 62:7)
    - Marine Midland Bank: check register (Box-folder 62:8)
    - Marine Midland Bank: deposited checks 1981-1983 (Box-folder 62:9)
    - Marine Midland Bank: documents (Box-folder 62:10)
    - Roulston Research Corporation (Box-folder 62:11)
    - Royal Bank of Scotland: correspondence 1982-1989 (Box-folder 62:12)
    - Royal Bank of Scotland: correspondence 1990-1992, 2004 (Box-folder 62:13)
    - Royal Bank of Scotland: bookkeeping records (Box-folder 62:14)
    - Royal Bank of Scotland: documents (Box-folder 62:15)
    - Royal Bank of Scotland: payments 1982-1990 (Box-folder 62:16)
    - Shearson-Lehman (Box-folder 63:1)
    - Smith Barney Shearson (Box-folder 63:2)
    - Miscellaneous banking (Box-folder 63:3)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: Budgets
    - Budgets 1982, 1983, 1985, 1987 (Box-folder 63:4)
    - Budgets 1991-1997 (Box-folder 63:5)
    - Bookkeeping 1980s (Box-folder 63:6)
    - Bookkeeping 1990s (Box-folder 63:7)
    - Budget notes (Box-folder 63:8)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: IRS
    - IRS correspondence 1950s (Box-folder 63:9)
    - IRS correspondence 1960s (Box-folder 63:10)
    - IRS correspondence 1970s (Box-folder 63:11)
    - Annual Report of Private Foundation 1979 (Box-folder 63:12)
    - State of New York, exempt organization certificate 1980 (Box-folder 63:13)
    - South Carolina corporation items 1982-1987 (Box-folder 63:14)
    - IRS correspondence (I) 1980s (Box-folder 64:1)
    - IRS correspondence (II) 1980s (Box-folder 64:2)
    - IRS correspondence (III) 1980s (Box-folder 64:3)
    - IRS correspondence (IV) 1980s (Box-folder 64:4)
    - Application for filing extension to IRS form 2758 1989 (Box-folder 64:5)
    - IRS correspondence (I) 1990s (Box-folder 64:6)
    - IRS correspondence (II) 1990s (Box-folder 64:7)
    - IRS correspondence (III) 1990s (Box-folder 64:8)
    - IRS correspondence (IV) 1990s (Box-folder 65:1)
    - IRS correspondence 2000s (Box-folder 65:2)
    - Directors and officers liability insurance (Box-folder 65:3)
    - Certification, IRS and New York state department (re. laws form 990 and related schedules) 1990 (Box-folder 65:4)
    - State of Tennessee, Department of Revenue documents (Box-folder 65:5)
    - Miscellaneous reports and documents (Box-folder 65:6)
    - New York State deficiencies report (draft) 1990s (Box-folder 65:7)
    - IRS Communications and Rulings prepared report, undated (I) (Box-folder 65:8)
    - IRS Communications and Rulings prepared report, undated (II) (Box-folder 65:9)
    - Dunvegan Foundation: New York State Deficiencies report (Box Box 65)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: Statement of Accounts
    - Financial statement 1961 (Box-folder 66:1)
    - Annual statements 1966-1969 (Box-folder 66:2)
    - Annual statements 1970-1979 (Box-folder 66:3)
    - Annual statements 1982-1989 (Box-folder 66:4)
    - Annual statements 1990-1992 (Box-folder 66:5)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: Tax Returns
    - Tax Returns 1957-1959 (Box-folder 66:6)
    - Tax Returns 1960-1969 (Box-folder 66:7)
    - Tax Returns 1970-1979 (Box-folder 66:8)
    - Tax Returns 1980-1983 (Box-folder 66:9)
    - Tax Returns 1984-1986 (Box-folder 66:10)
    - Tax Returns 1987-1989 (Box-folder 66:11)
    - Tax Returns 1990-1994 (Box-folder 67:1)
    - South Carolina Returns 1983-1986 (Box-folder 67:2)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: Trusts
    - Dunvegan Foundation memorial fund, memorials and honoraria 1994 (Box-folder 67:3)
    - Estate planning 2002 (Box-folder 67:4)
    - Family memorial fund 2002 (Box-folder 67:5)
    - Consideration of Dunvegan Foundation donation to the Ethel MacLeod Hylton Memorial Library November 17, 1964 (Box-folder 67:6)
    - Andy McCaskill memorial fund (Box-folder 67:7)
    - Anthony M. MacLeod bequest (Box-folder 67:8)
    - Charles A. McLeod, Jr. memorial fund (Box-folder 67:9)
    - John H. MacLeod memorial fund (Box-folder 67:10)
    - Frances Pearson Trust May 2003 (Box-folder 67:11)
    - Agnes McLeod Stephens memorial fund (Box-folder 67:12)
    - Lockerbie disaster relief appeal 1989 (Box-folder 67:13)
  - Financial-Legal Documents: Grants and Scholarships
    - Accountability for and control over grants and donations 1978 (Box-folder 67:14)
    - Chronologies of Dunvegan grants (Box-folder 67:15)
    - Listing of grants sponsored by the Dunvegan Foundation (Box-folder 67:16)
    - Atlanta Piper's Society (Box-folder 67:17)
    - Auburn University Grant (Box-folder 67:18)
    - Baylor College of Medicine: Vida Canaday McLeod Scholarship Endowment Fund (Box-folder 67:19)
    - Black Watch soccer club (Box-folder 67:20)
    - Carnegie Melon University (Box-folder 67:21)
    - Clan MacLeod scholarship fund and committee 1959 (Box-folder 67:22)
    - Clan MacLeod student aid fund 1994 (Box-folder 67:23)
    - Clann Alasdair Ruairdh music fund (Box-folder 67:24)
    - Coca Cola Foundation scholarships 1993 (Box-folder 67:25)
    - Colorado Youth Pipe Band 1989 (Box-folder 67:26)
    - Dunvegan Foundation scholarship committee 1958 (Box-folder 67:27)
    - Dunvegan Foundation scholarship 1982-1984 (Box-folder 67:28)
    - Exxon Corporation (Box-folder 67:29)
    - George Holiday McLeod scholarship (Box-folder 67:30)
    - Grant application form (blank) (Box-folder 67:31)
    - Grant letter draft from Ford Foundation (blank) (Box-folder 67:32)
    - H.P. MacNeal Cultural and Educational Committee of the Council of Scottish Clans and Associations, Inc. (Box-folder 67:33)
    - IncomEndowment Program (Box-folder 67:34)
    - Lyon College (Box-folder 67:35)
    - MacLeod Pipes and Drums (Box-folder 67:36)
    - Newsletter funding and foundation advertisements (Box-folder 67:37)
    - Old Dominion University, Institute of Scottish Studies (Box-folder 68:1)
    - Grants for piping (Box-folder 68:2)
    - Princeton University Scholarship (Box-folder 68:3)
    - Proposal to the Dunvegan Foundation for grant to write stories of sept families of Clan MacLeod (Box-folder 68:4)
    - Rio Grande Celtic Festival (Box-folder 68:5)
    - St. Andrews Presbyterian College (Box-folder 68:6)
    - St. Thomas Fund (Box-folder 68:7)
    - Scottish Fiddlers of California: Valley of the Moon Scottish Fiddling School (Box-folder 68:8)
    - Transfer grants: John Carter Brown Library (Box-folder 68:9)
    - Tenneco Corporation (Box-folder 68:10)
    - U.S. Piping Foundation (Box-folder 68:11)
    - West Virginia Highlanders Legion Pipe Band (Box-folder 68:12)
    - Wooster Marching Pipe Band (Box-folder 68:13)
    - Correspondence: various grants and scholarships 1970s-1980s (Box-folder 68:14)
    - Correspondence: various grants and scholarships 1990s (Box-folder 68:15)
  - Reports
    - Reports 1966-1967 (Box-folder 68:16)
    - Reports 1981-1985 (Box-folder 68:17)
    - Reports 1986 (Box-folder 69:1)
    - Reports 1987 (I) (Box-folder 69:2)
    - Reports (II) 1987 (Box-folder 69:3)
    - Reports (I) 1988 (Box-folder 69:4)
    - Reports (II) 1988 (Box-folder 69:5)
    - Reports (I) 1989 (Box-folder 69:6)
    - Reports (II) 1989 (Box-folder 69:7)
    - Reports 1990 (Box-folder 69:8)
    - Reports 1991 (Box-folder 70:1)
    - Reports (I) 1992 (Box-folder 70:2)
    - Reports (II) 1992 (Box-folder 70:3)
    - Reports (III) 1992 (Box-folder 70:4)
    - Reports 1993 (Box-folder 70:5)
    - Reports (I) 1994 (Box-folder 70:6)
    - Reports (II) 1994 (Box-folder 70:7)
    - Reports 1995-1996 (Box-folder 71:1)
    - Reports 1998-1999 (Box-folder 71:2)
    - Reports 2000 (Box-folder 71:3)
    - Reports 2003-2004 (Box-folder 71:4)
    - Reports: Miscellaneous (Box-folder 71:5)
    - Bound book: Dunvegan Foundation-Clan MacLeod Society, administrative 1980-1986 (Box Box 71)
    - Bound book: Dunvegan Foundation-Clan MacLeod Society, grants-projects 1980-1986 (Box Box 71)
    - Bound book: Dunvegan Foundation-Clan MacLeod Society, ACMS Part I 1980-1986 (Box Box 72)
    - Bound book: Dunvegan Foundation-Clan MacLeod Society, ACMS Part II 1980-1986 (Box Box 72)
    - Bound book: Dunvegan Foundation-Clan MacLeod Society, ACMS Part III 1980-1986 (Box Box 72)
    - Bound book: Dunvegan Foundation-Clan MacLeod Society, funding 1980-1986 (Box Box 73)
    - Bound book: Dunvegan Foundation-Clan MacLeod Society, tax-legal 1980-1986 (Box Box 73)
  - Workshops
    - Dunvegan Foundation Workshop I 1991 (Box-folder 73:1)
    - Dunvegan Foundation Workshop II 1992 (Box-folder 73:2)
    - Dunvegan Foundation Workshop III 1993 (Box-folder 73:3)
    - Dunvegan Foundation Workshop IV 1993 (Box-folder 73:4)
    - Dunvegan Foundation Workshop V 1994 (Box-folder 73:5)
    - Dunvegan Foundation Workshop 1997 (Box-folder 73:6)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Directories 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, 1998, 2003 (Box-folder 74:1)
    - Dunvegan Foundation luncheons February 4, 1967 (Box-folder 74:2)
    - Dunvegan Foundation questionnaires (Box-folder 74:3)
    - Dunvegan Foundation stationery (Box-folder 74:4)
    - Foundation printing sources (Box-folder 74:5)
    - Leadership directory July 1993 (Box-folder 74:6)
    - Handwritten notes (Box-folder 74:7)
- Cultural and Educational Resources 1950-2009.
  This series is divided into four sub-series in regard to art, music, poetry, exhibits, travel, and history within Clan MacLeod. Sub-series A: The Arts; Sub-series B: Exhibits; Sub-series C: Travel; Sub-series D: Miscellaneous Clan History. This series is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - The Arts
    - Jean MacLeod (Contralto): Recital, Times Hall, New York March 5, 1950 (Box-folder 74:8)
    - John MacLeod and Melita Kolin: Together with words and music (program) (Box-folder 74:9)
    - Poem-The Tartan (Box-folder 74:10)
    - Song sheets and booklets of Scottish songs for the MacLeods (Box-folder 74:11)
    - West Virginia Highlanders Bagpipe Band (Box-folder 74:12)
  - Exhibits
    - Dunvegan Cup (Box-folder 74:13)
    - Exhibition: Heirlooms and articles of MacLeod and Scottish Interest (Box-folder 74:14)
    - Grolier Club exhibit (Box-folder 74:15)
    - Scottish American Exhibit at John Carter Brown Library (Box-folder 74:16)
  - Travel
    - Clansman Colour Slides October 8, 1960 (Box-folder 74:17)
    - Home Exchange: Scotland (Box-folder 74:18)
    - The Evening Dispatch: The Island of the Fairy Flag August 14, 1956 (Box-folder 74:19)
    - A Journey to the Hebrides-A modern version by John H. MacLeod 1956 (Box-folder 74:20)
    - McLeod Ganj (town located in Northern India, named after Sir Donald McLeod, home of current Dalai Lama) (Box-folder 74:21)
    - MacLeod Tour 1956 (Box-folder 74:22)
    - The MacLeods Land Tour 1990 (Box-folder 74:23)
    - Isle of Skye: articles, clippings, brochures (Box-folder 74:24)
    - The Visitor: A Holiday Guide to Southwest Ross and Skye (Dunvegan article pg. 21) Summer 1990 (Box Oversize Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Clan History
    - Adventure in Fellowship by Remsen Bird November 12, 1953 (Box-folder 75:1)
    - Story: Alasdair Crotach's famous ox-roast on MacLeod's table (Box-folder 75:2)
    - Alexander McLeod historical road marker in North Carolina (Box-folder 75:3)
    - Chief Ives/Fairy Flag Legend (Box-folder 75:4)
    - Clan Gathering article on Chief John (Box-folder 75:5)
    - Clan heraldry (Box-folder 75:6)
    - Coat of Arms: MacLeod of the Lewes, Arms of the Chief (Box-folder 75:7)
    - Coat of Arms: MacLeod of MacLeod, Arms of the Chief (Box-folder 75:8)
    - Coats of Arms: MacLeod of MacLeod and MacLeod of Lewes (Box-folder 75:9)
    - Arms of the Chief: MacLeod of MacLeod and MacLeod of Lewes (Box-folder 75:10)
    - Color print of ACMS arms (Box-folder 75:11)
    - Reproduction of McIan's famous prints of the Scottish highlanders: MacLeod (Box-folder 75:12)
    - Clan MacLeod products (Box-folder 75:13)
    - The Clan MacLeod Society of America by Lamar W. McLeod 1954 (Box-folder 75:14)
    - Clan MacLeod clippings (Box-folder 75:15)
    - Clippings pertaining to Dame Flora MacLeod (Box-folder 75:16)
    - Clan MacLeod: A Thumbnail Sketch (Box-folder 75:17)
    - Clan Memories: A Personal Essay by Alexander C. McLeod (Box-folder 75:18)
    - Extract of matriculation of the arms of John MacLeod the Younger (copy) (Box-folder 75:19)
    - French definitions/versions of the name MacLeod (Box-folder 75:20)
    - Dr. Ralph M. Graham (Box-folder 75:21)
    - Greshornish House (Box-folder 75:22)
    - Hail to the Chief: Draft (Box-folder 75:23)
    - History of Ui Chapel (Box-folder 75:24)
    - Historical sketch of the MacLeod Clan, family, and castle by Reverend Donald MacDonald Millar (Box-folder 75:25)
    - The MacLeods and their castle (Box-folder 75:26)
    - The MacLeod family and its coat of arms (Box-folder 75:27)
    - McLeod family history 1977 (Box-folder 75:28)
    - MacLeod genealogy (Box-folder 75:29)
    - Various MacLeod histories (Box-folder 75:30)
    - Article: MacLeod, a prisoner of the Americans in 1776 (Box-folder 75:31)
    - The MacLeods of Trumpan (Box-folder 75:32)
    - The Northwest Highlands, from the Celts to modern times (Box-folder 75:33)
    - Origin of the Clan MacLeod (Box-folder 75:34)
    - Proclamation by Governor Richard W. Riley on Clan MacLeod Week April 14-20, 1986 (Box-folder 75:35)
    - Purdy Bevin McLeod, Jr.: resume/information (Box-folder 75:36)
    - Robert Burns and the MacLeods (Box-folder 75:37)
    - Ruairdh MacLeod (Box-folder 75:38)
    - Story of the Silver Charter as recounted in a personal letter from Barbara, (undated) (Box-folder 75:39)
    - Torquil Roderick MacLeod (brief biography and photo) (Box-folder 75:40)
    - Information: William Reynolds (Renny) MacLeod (Box-folder 75:41)
    - No. 3446 MacLeod of MacLeod-L.N.E.R. West Highland Engine (Box-folder 75:42)
    - Obituary: Sayre MacLeod (Box-folder 75:43)
    - Obituary: Daniel Murdock McCaskill (Box-folder 75:44)
    - Patriots and traitors address to Edinburgh Clan MacLeod Society, by Joan Wolridge Gordon 1968 (Box-folder 75:45)
    - Photocopy of information regarding Dame Flora (Box-folder 75:46)
    - Keynote address: The Warrior Clan 1992 (Box-folder 75:47)
    - Pauline Peters on People: Mother MacLeod, magazine article 1968 (Box Oversize Box 1)
    - Clipping of Chief John MacLeod, from the West Highland Free Press 1986 (Box Oversize Box 1)
    - Fitting Memorial for a Chief-Iona and its surroundings (Box Oversize Box 2)
    - Map and description of Rodel burial ground (Box Oversize Box 2)
- Publications 1929-2000.
  This series is divided into three sub-series pertaining to publications regarding the history of Clan MacLeod, as well as MacLeod families and individual members. Sub-series A: Histories-Clan MacLeod; Sub-series B: Histories: Individual/Family; Sub-series C: Miscellaneous. This series is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Histories: Clan MacLeod
    - Announcement for The MacLeods: The Migration of a Clan (Box-folder 76:1)
    - The Bannatyne Manuscript (copy) (Box-folder 76:2)
    - Clan MacLeod of the Carolinas by Catherine MacLeod Donaldson 1954 (Box-folder 76:3)
    - Clan MacLeod sailing barque (Box-folder 76:4)
    - Cover art and chapter art for The MacLeods: Genealogy of a Clan 1999 (Box-folder 76:5)
    - Clan MacLeod: Their Septs and Dependents (Box-folder 76:6)
    - Dunvegan Castle booklets and brochures (Box-folder 76:7)
    - The First Forty Years: The History of the Clan MacLeod Society in the United States of America; 1954-1994, by W. Jefferson Bryson and Harry E. Boyes (Box-folder 76:8)
    - Additional manuscript and deleted material from the The First Forty Years (Box-folder 76:9)
    - The MacLeods: Being a Short Historical and Genealogical Account of their Chiefs and Cadets (Box-folder 76:10)
    - National Geographic magazine article by Robert Reynolds: Over the Sea to Scotland's Skye 1952 (Box-folder 76:11)
    - Revision-The MacLeods: Genealogy of a Clan, section four, The MacLeods of Lewis with several septs including MacLeods of Rassay April 13, 1989 (Box-folder 76:12)
    - Scotland's Magazine and Scottish Country Life-two articles: This is Your Land, These are Your People, Clan MacLeod a message from Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod and MacLeod-A Proud Inheritance by Seton Gordon October 1965 (Box-folder 76:13)
    - Holiday Magazine article page 38: The Clans of Scotland September 1954 (Box Oversize Box 1)
  - Histories: Individual/Family
    - Biographical sketch of Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod (unpublished) 1962 (Box-folder 76:14)